Welcome back to Apush in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. Oh, the roaring 20s, what a
time to be alive. So much culture to
find this era of American history. So
why don't we walk down this 1920 street
and explore some cultural phenomena? The
first stop on this street is the lovely
bar, which we call a speakeasy, because
obviously alcohol is illegal in this
time period after the 18th Amendment.
Look at those lovely flappers dancing on
stage. Well, behind them a jazz band
fills the room with fast-paced rhythms
that symbolize a break from tradition
and the rise of a new American sound.
The bar is packed with people from
different backgrounds, a rare sight for
the time, all gathered in defiance of
one thing, prohibition. But the bar
isn't the only thing we see.
>> [music]
>> Our next stop is Harlem, New York, where
the Great Migration has caused a surge
of African-American culture known as the
Harlem Renaissance. In the building down
the street, I think I see two people,
Zora Neale Hurston and Langston Hughes,
who are proving that black people can
write great literature. But coming up
closer, I see two great artists of
Bessie Smith and Louis Armstrong
creating and performing lovely jazz to
all that can behold [music] it. Our last
stop here is the local library where
women finally gain new visibility in
society with their new right to vote in
women's suffrage movement. And I think I
even catch a sight of Alice Paul in the
corner helping out. Man, this era of
American history is truly something
special. Ahem. All right, that's enough
of that. Yes, this era looks incredible
on the surface. However, it's kind of
hard to explain, but it's all kind of
empty and trashy below the surface.
Prohibition causes widespread crime and
the growth of civil unrest. On top of
numerical quotas, immigrants get treated
even worse with these two Supreme Court
decisions. And though this era is
defined by vast amounts of money
everywhere, you got to remember what
comes literally right after this era.
The 1920s is all surface level. And the
reason it will collapse so quickly when
the depression hits is because
everything is built on beliefs and
borrowed money. The whole era seems cute
and incredible on the surface, but truly
everything you see is hanging on a tight
thread. So, before we end this topic, I
think it's only right since we talked
about all the good, let's talk about the
famous bad things that happened in the
'20s. The Scopes Monkey Trial upheld a
Tennessee law banning the teaching of
evolution. In Buck vs. Bell, the Supreme
Court ruled that it was okay to remove
some people's ability to have children
known as sterilization. And finally,
Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti had
a very unfair murder trial likely
because of their Italian heritage, and
they got sentenced to death and executed
despite their likely innocence. On the
screen now are AP-style questions for
this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.